Edna Greene Hines Papers
Edna Greene Hines Papers
1908-1958
1955-1958
Hines, Edna Greene.
0.5 linear ft.
American author and poet. Memorabilia and poems (printed, typescript, handwritten).
2741981
Biographical History
Edna Greene Hines (1888-1957) was an American author and poet. According to her obituary she was a graduate of Syracuse University, where she majored in English and Latin and was a member of the Board's Head Dramatic Society. In addition to her work as a poet she taught Latin in the Watertown, New York schools for many years and offered private tutoring.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Edna Greene Hines Papers contains poems and memorabilia.
Poems contains handwritten, typescript and published poems. Many are annotated by Hines as to when they were written, or for whom. Memorabilia contains photographs and Hines' obituary.
Arrangement of the Collection
Poems are in alphabetical order by title.
Subject and Genre Headings
Literature -- American Poetry; New York State; Women Authors; Hines, Edna Greene.; Candle in the night.; Captured dreams.; The endless trail.; Underneath the bough.; The valley of blue moon.; White butterflies.; American poetry -- 20th century.; Women poets.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Photographs.; Authors.; Poets.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Majority of collection, gift of Edna Green Hines, 1962.
Some items, gift of Raymond Piper, 1962.
Some items, transferred from University Archives, 1966.
Inventory
- Memorabilia
  - Obituary, Watertown Daily Times, 26 Dec 1957 (Box 1)
  - Photographs, circa 1908; 1955,; 1956,; undated (Box 1)
- Poems
  - Manuscript
    - A-Z, 1935-1939; 1942,; 1952-1958 (Box 1)
    - Untitled, 1952; 1956-1957 (Box 1)
  - Printed
    - Books, 1939-1957 (Box 1)
      Candle in the Night (1942)
      Captured Dreams (1957)
      The Endless Trail (1946)
      Underneath the Bough (1940)
      The Valley of Blue Moon (1939)
      White Butterflies (1949)
    - Clippings, undated (Box 1)